Guide to the Eva Asher Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Eva Asher Papers
1917-1983
RG 139
Yale University Divinity School Library
3
(6 boxes)
Substantive correspondence with Fukien Christian University students and administrators and extensive diary entries document the operations of a Christian university and the way of life of a single woman missionary in China. Eva Asher worked as treasurer and administrative assistant at Fukien Christian University, a Protestant mission-supported university in China, from 1923 to 1950.
Asher, Eva Mae
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Eva Mae Asher.
Biographical / Historical
Eva Asher worked as treasurer and administrative assistant at Fukien Christian University from 1923 to 1950.
Scope and Contents
Substantive correspondence with FCU students and administrators, and very full diary entries from throughout Eva Asher's service at Fukien Christian University, provide excellent documentation of the inner workings of a Christian university and the way of life of a single woman missionary in China. Collected material about Fukien Christian University supplements documentation found in YDSL Record Group No. 11, Archives of the United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia. Additional correspondence of Eva Asher can also be found in Record Group No. 11.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1918-1952
II. Diaries, 1923-1962
III. Writings, 1939-1940
IV. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1917-1950
V. Collected Material, 1926-1950, n.d.
VI. Photographs, 1918-1983
Missions -- China; Women missionaries -- China; Fuzhou Shi (Fujian Province, China); Asher, Eva; Fujian xie he da xue
- Correspondence, 1918-1952; Series I
  - Chen Hsi Cheng (John), FCU student, 1925-1927 (Box 1)
  - Chen Tze Tuan, FCU student, 1927-1932 (Box 1)
  - Lin, C. J., FCU president, 1929-1932 (Box 1)
  - Other representatives of FCU, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - Yen Hui-ching, FCU colleague/friend (wife of C. J. Lin), 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - Yang Hsin Pao, FCU student, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
  - Missionary colleagues, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Other correspondents, 1918-1929 (Box 1)
  - Representatives of the Associated Boards/ United Board for Christian Colleges in China, 1929-1952 (Box 1)
- Diaries, 1923-1962; Series II
  - Diaries, 1923-1928, 1930-1932 (Box 2)
  - Diaries, 1933-1941 (Box 3)
  - Diaries, 1941-1949 (Box 4)
  - Diaries, 1950-1962 (Box 5)
- Writings, 1939-1940; Series III
  - Student papers of EMA, 1939-1940 (Box 5)
  - "No Blackout in Christian Missions in China", 1940 (Box 5)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1917-1950; Series IV
  - Miscellaneous, 1917-1950 (Box 5)
- Collected Material, 1926-1950, n.d.; Series V
  - Re. Fukien Christian University, 1928-1942, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Misc., incl. re. Chinese porcelain, silk, characters, political events, etc., 1926-1950, n.d. (Box 5)
- Photographs, 1918-1983; Series VI
  - Album: Scenes in Fujian province, at Fukien Christian University, missionary colleagues, 1923-1929 (Box 6)
  - Loose photos: EMA portraits and personal photos; Chinese friends, students, colleagues; Western friends and relatives; Scenes, primarily in Fujian province, 1918-1983, n.d. (Box 6)